Mansi Rajora

BTECH GGSIPU 2016-2020

RZF 772/20 Street Number -13, Dwarka Sector 8, South West Delhi -110077, INDIA

□ (+91) 8178656614 | ■ mansirajora09@gmail.com | • Mansi-Rajora09 | • mansi rajora

Summary_

To have a rewarding and fulfilling career in which i can satisfy my thirst for knowledge and practice the lessons learnt to deliver quality work to the best of my abilities, for the betterment of my employer and in return expect to be enriched in terms of knowledge and experience.

Education

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University

Delhi

B.Tech. IN Informational Technology

Apr 2018

· Aggregate Percentage -78

12, CBSE

Delhi

GYAN SAGAR PUBLIC SCHOOL

May 2014

Aggregate Percentage - 7810, CBSE

Delhi

GYAN SAGAR PUBLIC SCHOOL

May 2012

• CGPA 9.6

Work Experience _____

Intern Lucideus Okhla Phase , Delhi

COMPUTER NETWORK, KALI LINUX

Jun. 2017 - Aug. 2017

- · Worked as Ethical Hacker.
- · Understand the types of Malware, trozans ,viruses to the System and how to protect the System from them

Intern DRDO Civil Lines, Delhi

COMPUTER NETWORK, JAVA

Jun. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Worked on Error Correction and Detection Techniques.
- Worked on parity check and cyclic Redundancy check

Software Developer BlackNGreen

Gurgaon, Haryana

SPRING, JAVA, C, PHP, ACTIVEMQ, JWT TOKENS, MONGO, MYSQL, JAVASCRIPT, JENKINS

August. 2018 - Present

- Fixed bugs on existing projects built in Java and PHP.
- Worked on a product from scratch understanding the need.
- Created the system design keeping scalability in mind.
- Coded complete backend in java ,spring, used mysql for database and redis for caching.
- Created a system that helps operators in leveraging their zero balance customers to create new revenue streams and enhance customer retention. The product enables users and brands to engage over meaningful advertisements, in exchange for which brands provide free data MBs to the users.
- Created a voice broadcasting platform. That can be used by Governments and Corporates to send calls to mass user-base. Reach can handle very large numbers of calls each day.

Skills

DevOps Git

Back-end Spring Boot and MVC, Java, REST API, JWT Tokens, Servlet

Front-end JS, HTML5,CSS, React

DBMS MySQL,Elasticsearch,MongoDB

Strong Core CS Concepts Computer Networks, Operating System, Data Structures And Algos

Miscellaneous System Design And Distributed Systems, Shell Scripting

Tools SVN, Gitlab, JIRA Languages English, Hindi

Extracurricular Activity _____

November 12, 2020 Mansi Rajora · Résumé 1

Software Development Dwarka, New Delhi

Passion Jun. 2010 - Active

- Active in various communities like slack, stackoverflow-https://stackoverflow.com/users/15363173/mansi.
- Love to read opensource code mostly in Java, Spring Boot.
- · Looking forward to contribute to opensource, made a few pull requests in multiple open source repositories
- Love to write blogs on medium
- Love to read about new Technolgies.
- Github Username- Mansi-Rajora09

Projects

Library Management System

GGSIPU

JAVA, HTML, CSS, JS, MYSQL

- motive of making this project is user and admin can operate the library from their own computer. and we made it simplest project as we make
 this simpler for user to use.
- Complete back-end in Java.
- · Complete database for peers in MySql.

Quiz Logo GGSIPA

Mysql, Java, Redis, ActiveMq

· This project looks similar to online Testing where each question consisting of 4 options and the user have to select One option

Arduino POV GGSIPU

ARDUINO IDE

• Persistence of Vision, or POV, occurs when a visual image seems to persist continuously when a stream of light is repeatedly interrupted for very brief instances and does not enter our eyes during those durations.

Reach (OBD/SMS/WhatsApp,Email)

BNG,Gurgaon

SPRING BOOT, REACT, MYSQL, ACTIVEMQ

• Enterprise Application With High level Reporting:- Reach is a voice broadcasting platform. That can be used by Governments and Corporates to send calls to mass user-base. Reach can handle very large numbers of calls each day..

DatacomBNG,Gurgaon

Spring Boot, Mysql ,React

- Datacom helps operators in leveraging their zero balance customers to create new revenue streams and enhance customer retention. The
product enables users and brands to engage over meaningful advertisements, in exchange for which brands provide free data MBs to the users.

CCIBNG,Gurgaon

PHP, MYSQL, JAVASCRIPT

- provide operators an Interface where they can get all information of user whether it is call related, subscription related, Billing related adding number in DND and so on.
- User can be Subscribed and unsubscribed to the Services using this platform

SCP BNG, Gurgaon

JAVA, XML PARSERS, ACTIVEMQ, MYSQL

• Created an application where by drag and drop flow is created in XML format which can be used by other module (system) to decide the next step

CMS BNG, Gurgaon

JAVA, WOWZA, ACTIVEMQ, MYSQL

• CMS is a platform for video content management. It have features like upload video content with their meta data. CMS will handle video quality with resolution for different screen. Is also create meta data for streaming software (Wowza streaming). It has API to handle user request and provides all Video on demand features like User wise home screen data, Recommended data, dynamic category creation etc.

DCBBNG, Gurgaon

JAVASCRIPT,PHP,MONGO

• Direct carrier billing (DCB) is an online mobile payment method that enables consumers to purchase our services. It works across mobile devices (smartphones) and is accessible to any user with a subscription or prepaid account with a mobile operator.

Honors & Awards

2011-2012 Prizes, Win Several Prize in Debate Competition

Delhi Delhi

2010 **Medals**, Win Prizes in Swimming and Skating Competition

India

2016 **Bronze Medal**, tug of War



Blogs on MediumNew Delhi, IndiaDEV WITH VISHALJune. 2020

- Write blogs on Technologies https://medium.com/@mansi $_74608$.